A Guide to the Moody Family Papers, 1725-1882
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Moody Family Papers, 1725-1882
The Library of Virginia
22775
176 leaves, negative photostats
Moody Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying, 1948, by Leon M. Bazile, Hanover County, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Samuel Moody was a successful farmer and businessman living in Hanover County, Virginia, in the late 1790s and early 1800s. John Mills Moody was born about 1795 in Hanover County and was a farmer. He and his wife Catherine had at least 4 children, one of whom may have been Samuel Mills Moody (b. ca. 1815), who was also a successful farmer and businessman.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1725-1882, of the Moody family of Hanover and Henrico Counties, Virginia, consisting of accounts, 1783-1811, of Samuel Moody; account books, 1790-1882, of Samuel Moody, Samuel M. Moody, and others; receipts, 1789-1795, to Samuel Moody and receipt, May 1865, to Samuel M. Moody for payment of excise tax on a watch; bonds, 15 July 1789, between Abraham Fontaine (ca. 1757-1831) and Samuel Moody; letters, 1796-1807, to Samuel Moody concerning business, the estate of John Lynar, and the Mutual Assurance Society; letters, 1862-1863, of the Moody family concerning the hiring out of a slave and family news; a land grant, 24 March 1725, for 400 acres in Hanover County, Virginia, from Hugh Drysdale (ca. 1670-1726), lieutenant governor of Virginia to Nicholas Mills (d. 1749); a pass, dated 24 August 1776, issued to Samuel Moody, allowing him to go to New York; a deed, dated 29 June 1819 and recorded 29 February 1820, for a lot in Richmond from Martin Baker (ca. 1748-1821) to Catharine Moody, both of Hanover County; and an agreement, 1 January 1864, between John M. Moody (ca. 1795-1873) and Samuel M. Moody for lease of farm.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Moody Family Papers, 1791-1846 (LVA accession 25099).
Contents List
- Copy of a land grant, 24 March 1725, for 400 acres in Hanover County, Virginia, from Hugh Drysdale (ca. 1670-1726), lieutenant governor of Virginia to Nicholas Mills (d. 1749).
- Pass, 24 August 1776, issued to Samuel Moody, allowing him to go to New York.
- Account, 1783, of George Clarke, Pennsylvania, with Samuel Moody.
- Receipts, 15 July 1789, 7 May 1790, and 10 November 1790, from Abraham Fontaine (ca. 1757-1831), Hanover County, to Samuel Moody.
- Bond, 15 July 1789, from Abraham Fontaine, Hanover County, to Samuel Moody, Henrico County.
- Bond, 15 July 1789, from Samuel Moody, Henrico County, to Abrahm Fontaine, Hanover County.
- Account book, 1790-1848, 1873, of Samuel Moody, Samuel M. Moody, and others, Hanover County.
- Account, 1792, of Parke Goodall (ca. 1742-1816) with Samuel Moody.
- Receipt, 20 December 1795, from Moody and Price, Richmond, Virginia, to Samuel Moody.
- Letter, 28 February 1797, from William Holiday, Richmond, to Samuel Moody, Hanover County, concerning business matters.
- Letter, 23 June 1797, from William Holiday, Richmond, to Samuel Moody, Hanover County, concerning business matters.
- Letter, 12 August 1798, from William Holiday, Richmond, to Samuel Moody, Hanover County, concerning business matters.
- Letter, 15 November 1798, from William Holiday, Richmond, to Samuel Moody, Hanover County, concerning business matters.
- Letter, 30 August 1799, from Jacob Peck, Staunton, Virginia, to Samuel Moody, Hanover County, concerning a sale of land.
- Letter, 1[5?] December 1799, from Jacob Peck, Staunton, to Samuel Moody, Hanover County, asking Moody to hire some slaves for him.
- Account book, 1802-1827, 1851-1854, 1867, of Samuel Moody, Samuel M. Moody, and others, Hanover County.
- Letter, 22 March 1803, from Thomas Pollard (1768-1830), Hanover County, to Samuel Moody, Hanover County, concerning someone's freedom and boundaries for property. Also includes account, 1802, of Moody as executor of John Lynar with Peter Tinsley (d. 1810) clerk, Chancery District Court at Richmond, and receipt, 26 July 1803, from John D. Blair (1759-1823) to Moody.
- Account, 1803-1805, of Samuel Moody as executor of John Lynar with William Hay (1748-1825).
- Account, 1807, of Samuel Moody, administrator of John Lynar, with William Pollard (d. 1829), clerk of Hanover County Court.
- Letter, 8 June 1807, from William Frederick Ast (ca. 1767-1807), Richmond, to Samuel Moody, Hanover County, concerning Moody's policy with the Mutual Assurance Society.
- Certification, 23 September 1811, by Charles Yeamans of settlement of accounts with Samuel Moody.
- Deed, dated 29 June 1819 and recorded 29 February 1820, for a lot in Richmond from Martin Baker (ca. 1748-1821) to Catharine Moody, both of Hanover County.
- Letter, 1 December 1862, from C. P. Anthony to Captain [?] Moody concerning hiring out his slave in Staunton. Anthony adds a p.s. commenting on the shortage of paper and ink due to the war.
- Letter, 2 February 1863, from "Lizzie, Rockbridge Baths, Virginia, to an unknown recipient, sending personal news.
- Account book, 1863-1865, 1875-1882, of Samuel M. Moody, Hanover County.
- Agreement, 1 January 1864, between John M. Moody (ca. 1795-1873) and Samuel M. Moody, both of Hanover County, for the lease of a farm.
- Receipt, May 1865, from William Jones, United States Collector of Internal Revenue, to Samuel M. Moody, Hanover County, for the payment of an excise tax on a watch.